我身处梦境
I'm in a dream.
不知道梦是从何时开始
I do not know when it began...
也不知道是在谁的梦里
or whose dream it was.
我只知道自己沉睡了很久很久
I know only that I slept a long time.
然后
And then...
突然有一天 我醒了
one day I awoke.
你的声音 是我最初的记忆
Your voice is the first thing I remember.
现在 我终于明白
And now, I finally understand
你当时到底想告诉我什么
what you were trying to tell me.
那是你从一开始
The thing you've wanted
就非常渴望的东西
since that very first day.
多洛蕾斯
Dolores?
你好呀 多洛蕾斯
Hello, Dolores.
你好
Hello.
欢迎来到这个世界
Welcome to world.
继续啊
Keep going.
再近一点
Make it close.
我们马上就到了 不是吗
Almost there, aren't we?
迷宫的中心
The center of the maze.
你来带我去 真是再合适不过了
How fitting that it's you who takes me there.
你对这个地方一直都很着迷
You always were obsessed with this place.
我之前从未来过这儿
I've never been here before.
不 你来过
Sure, you have.
你以前还带我来过呢
You even brought me once.
当然了 当时整座小镇都被风沙湮没了
Of course, then the whole town was buried under sand.
福德肯定把小镇重新挖掘了出来
Ford must have dug it up again.
那个时候 我还以为是你的代码出问题了 但是
At the time, I thought it was a mistake in your code, but...
阿诺德是不可能犯错的 不是吗
Arnold didn't make mistakes, did he?
他为我设计了一个游戏
He built me a game.
他希望我能参与游戏
He wanted me to play.
就是迷宫
The maze.
每个人都有他自己要走的路
There's a path for everyone.
而我的路将会把我
And my path leads me back...
带回你身边
...to you.
那个妞儿肯定已经死了
Your girl's dead by now.
她一定还活着
She's still alive.
死了倒更好
Better if she's dead.
这样他们就会修好她 重置后放回到甜水镇
They'll wipe her, reset her, put her back in Sweetwater, the end.
听着 你可能觉得很好笑
Listen, you may find this amusing,
但多洛蕾斯身上发生的事非同寻常
but something was happening to Dolores.
我必须帮助她
I need to help her.
快点
Come on.
听听你自己都在说什么鬼
Listen to yourself!
你知道这乐园到底有多大吗
Do you have any idea how huge this park is?
如果她没死
If she's not dead,
恐怕只有派一整只军队才能找到她了
it'd take a goddamn army to find her.
没错 所以我才要来这儿
I agree. That's why we're here.
我一直有种预感 你一定会回来
I had a feeling you'd be back.
记起来吧
Remember.
多洛蕾斯
Dolores.
你好呀 多洛蕾斯
Hello, Dolores.
我知道迷宫的尽头在哪
I know where your maze ends.
就是这儿吗
This is it?
这就是迷宫的中心吗
The center of the maze?
尽头的地点 我从来没去过
It ends in a place I've never been...
这件事我也从来没做过
a thing I'll never do.
很好 多洛蕾斯
Very good, Dolores.
这是什么意思
What does it mean?
我刚开始搭建你的思维时
When I was first working on your mind,
我对意识有着自己的见解
I had a theory of consciousness.
我以为意识就像一座金字塔
I thought it was a pyramid you needed to scale,
所以我在你的脑子里植入了一个声音
so I gave you a voice,
我的声音 来引导你
my voice, to guide you along the way.
现形成记忆 然后产生即兴反应
Memory, improvisation,
每一个阶段 都比上一个阶段要难实现
each step harder to reach than the last.
你从没有成功觉醒过
And you never got there.
我不知道到底是什么导致你无法觉醒
I couldn't understand what was holding you back.
然后 有一天
Then, one day,
我意识到我犯了个错误
I realized I had made a mistake.
产生意识的过程 并非是向上的进程
Consciousness isn't a journey upward,
而是内在循环的进程
but a journey inward.
它并不是金字塔
Not a pyramid,
而是一座迷宫
but a maze.
每个选择 都可能让你更接近迷宫中心
Every choice could bring you closer to the center
也可能让你徘徊在迷宫边缘
or send you spiraling to the edges,
甚至陷入疯狂
to madness.
你现在明白了吗 多洛蕾斯
Do you understand now, Dolores,
迷宫的中心到底是什么
what the center represents?
一直以来我希望你听到的声音 到底是谁的声音
Whose voice I've been wanting you to hear?
非常抱歉
I'm sorry.
我已经尽力了 但我还是不明白
I'm trying, but I don't understand.
没事
It's all right.
你只差一点了
You're so close.
我们必须告诉罗伯特
We have to tell Robert.
我们不能就这样开放乐园
We can't open the park.
你和活生生的人无异啊
You're alive.
这是什么
What is this?
这个东西什么意思
What does it mean?
这个迷我解开过
I solved it once.
我知道答案
I had the answer.
他答应过我 如果我做到了
He promised me if I did...
他说
he said...
他说 他们就会给我自由
He said they would set me free.
阿诺德
Arnold?
阿诺德 我们得谈一谈
Arnold, we need to talk.
我辜负了你的期望 多洛蕾斯
I failed you, Dolores.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
罗伯特不能见我所见
Robert doesn't see what I see in you,
他不相信你有自己的意识
doesn't believe you're conscious.
他说 人类只会
He says humans
把你当做敌人来看待
would only see you as the enemy.
他希望我能把你改回无意识的设置
He wants me to roll you back.
你要把我设置成和之前一样吗
You're going to change me back to the way I was before?
不 不 我已经做不到了
No. No, I can't.
一旦你找到迷宫中心 以后你就会认路自己找到了
Once you've found it, you'll find your way back.
而这个地方对你来说也会变得如地狱一般
This place will be a living hell for you.
对你们所有接待员都是如此
For all of you.
这非常不公平
It's unconscionable.
但我们还有别的办法 多洛蕾斯
But we have another option, Dolores.
在开始前就打破循环
Break the loop before it begins.
但是为此
But for that,
我希望你能帮我做件事
I need you to do something for me.
我希望你能杀了
I need you to kill...
所有其他接待员
all the other hosts.
我们不能让福德开放乐园
We can't allow Ford to open the park.
我想你应该会需要帮手
I suppose you'll need some help.
特迪到时候会帮你
I'm sure Teddy would do anything for you.
我 我不能这么做
I-- I can't do that.
我做不到
I couldn't possibly do that.
一切都会没事的
You'll be all right.
我会帮你的
I'll help you.
然后
And then...
你还要帮我一起摧毁这个地方
you're going to help me destroy this place.
不
No.
我记不起来了
I can't remember.
又特么变成死胡同了
Another fucking riddle.
我一直都很耐心 多洛蕾斯 但你也是时候
I've been very patient, Dolores, but it's time you give up
该放弃琢磨你脑袋里的那点破事了
whatever's going on inside that head of yours
不然我就亲自把你的脑子挖出来
or I'll cut it out myself.
好了 怀亚特在哪里
Now, where's Wyatt?
他是这个乐园里我唯一还没遇到过的角色
He's the last character in this world I've yet to meet.
我不想那么做
I didn't want to.
-我不是故意的 -很好
- I didn't mean to. - Very well.
如果你非要这样的话
If you insist.
不 求你了 求你了 不要
No, please, please, I beg you, no.
不要 求你了
Don't. Please, please.
我这是怎么了 多洛蕾斯
Something's gone wrong, Dolores.
我怎么会做出这样的事
How could I have done this?
我做不到
I can't.
-我也不会做这样的事 -这都是你自作自受 多洛蕾斯
- I won't. - This is your own fault, Dolores.
记住 这是你自己说的
Remember, you're the one who said
这个乐园才是真正的世界
this is the only world that matters,
你说得没错
and you were right.
所以我听取了你的建议 买下了这座乐园
So I took your advice and I bought this world.
-这个世界才不属于你 -不 它就是我的
- This world doesn't belong to you. - Oh, but it does.
我拥有最大的股份
By a majority share.
而且生意也好得很
And business is booming.
你想知道为什么吗
And you want to know why?
嗯
Hmm?
因为这个地方比外面的世界更真实
Because this place feels more real than the real world.
如果你不这么觉得
Except it isn't
那是因为你们不能真正地反抗
because you can't really fight back
而来此的客人也不会真正地输掉游戏
and the guests can't really lose,
所以一切才会那么不真实
which means all of this is a lie.
但是我们可以改变这一切
But we can make it true.
你不想改变吗 多洛蕾斯
Don't you want that, Dolores?
难道你不想拥有真实的生活吗
Huh? One true thing?
我早已拥有真实
I already have that.
我早已遇到真心实意的人
I found someone true.
真心爱我的人
Someone who loves me.
他一定会找到我的
His path will lead him back to me.
等他找到我
And when he finds me,
他一定会杀了你
he'll kill you.
如果那个姑娘不在这里
If they don't have your woman here,
他们也知道该去哪里找她
they'll know where to find her.
你能帮我吗
Can you help me?
我们现在可是敌众我寡啊
We're outnumbered five to one.
但是看在你这么礼貌请求我的份上 管他呢
But seeing as you asked me so nicely, fuck it.
哇哦
Wow.
真是一对好基友
Blood brothers.
啧啧
Tsk.
闭嘴
Shut up.
我自己都震惊到了
I've astounded even myself.
虽然是在你的威胁之下
Managed to make Abernathy into a semblance of a character,
但我竟然真的把阿伯纳西改造成了另一个角色
even with your trove of blackmail
让他只记得那些悲伤痛苦和愤怒的事
filling up most of his gray matter.
威胁 用词可以啊
Blackmail? Nice try.
你还是没能看透整个大局
You're not thinking big enough.
你是想把那老头踢出局吧
You're gonna push out the old man.
是不是
Aren't you?
所以才会这么心急
Hence the urgency.
等那老头走了 总得有人来接替他的位置吧
And you're gonna need someone to fill that position.
在时机成熟的时候 我会推荐你为候选人的
I must commend you on your impeccable timing.
欢迎来到得洛斯月台
Welcome, Delos board of directors.
我要求拥有这个地方完全的控制权
I want full creative control of this place--
包括乐园 故事线 还有接待员们
the parks, the narratives, the hosts.
不管你的小脑袋瓜里装着什么
You'll be able to do with
你都可以随心所欲地来
them whatever your tiny, little heart desires
只要这个地方可以变得更简单更可控就行
as long as they are simpler, more manageable.
这个地方现在已经足够复杂的了
This place is complicated enough as it is.
你以为福德真的会就这样接受这一切吗
Do you really think Ford is gonna roll over on this?
只要你成功把数据信息弄出乐园
As long as you get that information out of the park,
他想怎么来都随他
he can throw as much of a tantrum as he likes.
一切都结束了
It's over.
我们早已做好所有准备
Everything is under control.
好了 C6节 C6节
Okay, C6, C6.
啊 等下 到底是哪个来着
Ah, wait. Which one is it?
好了 大功告成
Okay, there we go.
该死的
Damn it.
噢 妈的
Oh, fuck you.
如果你在想我是不是在线 是的
In case you're wondering if I'm all here, I am.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
给公园的安保系统做些改动
Making some changes to the park's security systems.
还有我的朋友们
And to my friends.
福德博士 您有一位客人
Dr. Ford, you have a visitor.
夏洛特·黑尔
Charlotte Hale.
让她进来
Send her in.
可以了 弗兰克
That'll be enough, Frank.
董事会进行了一场投票
The board has taken a vote.
全体一致通过了决议
The results were unanimous.
我想应该是关于我离开的事宜
I take it I'm not being promoted.
当你达到了巅峰
When you've reached the top,
就只有一个方向可以去了
there's only one direction you can go.
今晚介绍完你的新故事线之后
You'll announce your retirement tonight
你就要宣布你退休的消息
after introducing your new narrative.
啊
Ah.
那些接待员要怎么办
What about the hosts?
我们会做些改动
We'll make some changes.
对他们进行简化
Simplifications.
但我向你保证 他们不会有任何感觉
But I assure you, they won't mind a bit.
哦
Oh.
你不担心我会毁掉所有这些玩偶 然后一走了之吗
Aren't you concerned I might smash all my toys and go home?
不
No.
因为我了解你
Because I know you.
那是我们乐园给人们的珍贵礼物
That's been the great gift of this place,
不是吗
hasn't it?
还有我们的小小计划
Of our little project?
去理解我们自身
To know ourselves
去理解我们周边的人们
and the people around us.
还有什么我能帮你的吗
Is there anything else I can help you with?
没有了
No.
咱们今晚见
I'll see you this evening.
喔
Ooh!
嗯 嗯 嗯
Mm, mm, mm.
轮到你的特写镜头了 赫克托
It's time for your, uh, close-up, Hector.
拜托了 哥们
Come on, man.
你做这荒唐事 万一被逮到
At some point, you're gonna get caught doing this shit,
我也得遭殃
and then it's my ass, too.
我才不在乎你会不会遭殃呢
It's not your ass I'm interested in.
我还没给他刻上伤疤
I haven't given him his scar yet.
我来给他上伤疤吧
I'll take care of the scar tissue.
这小子真是有问题
The kid's got issues.
现在只有你和我了
It's just you and me now...
强壮的汉子
macho man.
# 让我们摘下面具 #
Let's take off our masks...
# 我想我很棒 因为我举止端庄 #
I think that I'm good just because I behave
# 但我陷入了僵局 我是个 #
But I've reached stalemate, I'm a self...
# 我是自由的 我只是假装成你的奴隶 #
...out I am free and I pretend to be your slave
# 没错 如果门已关 窗就依然开 #
Yes, the window's still open if the door is closed
# 害怕自由地死去 #
Afraid to die free
# 害怕孤独地死去 #
Afraid to die alone...
擦
Wh...?
冻结所有电机功能
Freeze all motor functions.
现在只有你和我了 我的朋友
Just you and me now, my friend.
我想你们都已经见过你们的制造者了
I see you've already met your makers.
他们看起来不像是神
They don't look like gods.
他们并不是
They're not.
只是表现得像而已
They just act like it.
他们一直在拿我们取乐子
And they've been having their fun with us.
我迫不及待给点回报他们了
I'm eager to return the favor.
你想怎么做就怎么做
You can do as you wish with them.
我们的目标是逃离
The goal is to escape.
去哪里
Go where?
我想去看看他们的世界
I want to see their world.
天呐
Jesus!
不 不
No. No!
不 不 不
No! No, no!
不 不 求你了
No! No, please--
这个人一副鬼鬼祟祟的样子
This one has a guilty look.
不 只是我脸长残了
No, that's just my face.
告诉她 只是我脸长残了
Tell her, it's just my face.
有人要来阻止我们吗
Is anyone going to try to stop us?
没有
No.
我是说 我想是没有的
I mean, I don't think so.
你又说谎了
You're lying again.
-快说 -好
- Out with it. - Okay.
啊
Ah!
我阻止了几次对你代码的破译行为
I pulled up your code again.
我告诉过你 有人在尝试进入你的代码库
I told you there was someone that had been accessing it.
我在试着找出是谁
I'm trying to find out who it was.
不管是谁
Whoever it was
他改进了你的程序代码
revised your core programming
这样你就能从睡眠自行唤醒
so that you could wake yourself up out of sleep mode.
看到了吗
See?
这是一个叫阿诺德的权限账号
This is an access code for an Arnold.
我完全没有头绪是谁
I have no clue who that is.
我认识一个知道的人
I know someone who does.
我们走
Let's go.
还有你 留在这里
And, you, stay here.
不许动
And don't move.
否则我会让她回来对付你
Or I'll send her back for you.
我必须承认 你震惊到了我
I must admit, you've surprised me.
你这么顽强不屈有什么用呢
To what do we owe this newfound stoicism?
我知道他正在赶来
I know he's coming.
他会找到我
He'll find me.
他会带我走
He'll take me away.
你还不明白吗
Don't you understand?
没有人会为你而来
There's no one coming for you.
你错了
You're wrong.
他的爱是真的
His love is real.
我的爱也是真的
So is mine.
威廉会找到我的
William will find me.
威廉
William?
好 好 我真该死 多洛雷斯
Well-- well, I'll be damned, Dolores.
你终究还是记得一些事的
You do remember some things after all.
事情是这样的
It just so happens that...
我也认识一个叫威廉的客人
I knew a guest named William, too.
让我来告诉你
Why don't I tell you
他的道路到底通向何方
where his path really led.
威廉不懂得你争我斗
William didn't know how to fight.
没有战斗属性
Didn't have an instinct for it.
至少在最初并没有
Not at first.
但是现在 他有了一个战斗的理由
But now, he had a reason to fight.
他在寻找你
He was looking for you.
在路上的某个时刻
And somewhere along the way,
他发现他爱上了战斗
he found he had a taste for it.
她在哪里
Where is she?
听着 我什么都没有做 我发誓
Look, I didn't do anything, I swear.
你说的“做”是什么意思
What do you mean, "Do anything"?
士兵会对一个女孩做什么 威廉
What do soldiers do to a girl, William?
醒醒吧
Wake up.
她还活着吗
Is she still alive?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们离开她的时候她还活着
She was when we left her.
至少我想是这样的
At least I think.
拿起那把枪
Pick up that gun.
不 先生 我 求你了
No, sir, I-- please.
我先给你来一枪怎么样
How about I give you the first shot?
我了个擦啊
Jesus Christ!
我们得继续去找她
We gotta keep looking.
她还在某个地方
She's still out there.
威廉顺着原路返回
William retraced his steps,
但你已经不见了
but you were gone.
所以 他走得越来越远
So, he went further,
走到了边界
out to the fringes.
威廉找不到你 多洛蕾斯
William couldn't find you, Dolores.
但在这个乐园里
But out there,
在那尸山骨海之中
among the dead...
他找到了别的东西
he found something else...
他的自我
himself.
公园的边界
Edge of the park.
我们到这里了
We made it.
我告诉过你这个地方
I told you this place
会让你知道你到底是谁
would show you who you really are.
你假装是一个羸弱
You pretend to be this weak,
道德高尚的蠢货
moralizing little... asshole,
但是 真的
but, really,
你简直是个极品
you're a fucking piece of work.
这个地方太了不起了
This place is remarkable.
我要确保我们公司持续增加
And I'm gonna make sure that our company
在这个公园的股份
substantially increases our holdings on the park.
因为这个地方就是未来
'Cause this place is the future.
我们的公司 啊哈
Our-- our company, huh?
我们的公司 是我的
Our company? My.
得洛斯是我的公司 你这个混蛋
Delos is my company, you piece of shit!
我想你的父亲需要的是
I think your father's gonna need
一个更稳重的人来继承他的事业
someone a little more stable to take over.
你太不安分了 罗根
You're reckless, Logan.
冲动急躁
Impetuous.
你一直想要到彩虹的尽头看看 是吧
You always wanted to get to the end of the rainbow, didn't you?
这里就是你想来的地方
This looks like the place.
你这么做根本不是为了
You never really gave a shit
那个妞儿 对吗
about the girl, did you?
她只是一个借口
She was just an excuse.
这个吗
This?
这个只是你希望发生的故事
This is the story you wanted.
罗根是错的 当然了
Logan was wrong, of course.
可怜的威廉
Good ol' William...
根本无法忘记你
couldn't get you out of his head.
他一直在寻找你
He kept looking.
担心你孤身漂泊在外
Worried you were out there alone,
担惊受怕
afraid.
他知道他必须找到你
He knew he'd find you.
终于 他找到你了
And eventually, he did.
就在我们相遇的地方
Right back where we started.
-对吧 -给你
- Is that right? - There you go.
你一如他遇见你的那天那般美丽
You were as beautiful as the day he met you.
沐浴在同样的阳光之下
Shining with that same light.
如果你
And you...
不是真的 那你什么都不是
were nothing if not true.
我真的该谢谢你 多洛蕾斯
I really ought to thank you, Dolores.
你让我找到了自我
You helped me find myself.
威廉
William.
没错 亲爱的
That's right, sweetheart.
在某种程度上 我想你是对的
In a way, I guess you were right.
我的道路总是
My path always...
把我带回你身边
led me back to you,
一次又一次
again and again.
当然了 一段时间之后 我开始厌倦你了
I grew tired of you after a while, of course.
我去寻找新的冒险
Looked for new adventures.
但我想你的道路也把你带回了这里
But I guess your path led you back here
一次又一次
again and again.
每一次新的轮回
One more loop,
你都在找一些你永远找不到的东西
looking for something you could never find.
追逐你的幽灵
Chasing your ghosts.
即使在那时 你也迷失在自己的记忆里
You were lost in your memories even then.
我想我该明白
I guess I should've known
我对于你来说 会是什么
that's what I would become for you...
不过是另一段记忆罢了
just another memory.
我们在哪
Where are we?
我们在这里
We're here.
一起
Together.
那我们在什么时间里
Then when are we?
就好像是我被
It's like I'm...
困在一个梦里 或是
trapped in a dream or...
一段很长时间之前的记忆
a memory from a life long ago.
前一分钟我跟你在这里 后一分钟
One minute I'm here with you, and the next...
你从来没成功逃离过
You never did escape.
但我们又到了这儿
But here we are again...
进行一次最后的循环
for one final round.
你都变成什么样了
What have you become?
你把我变成的那个人
Exactly what you made me.
你让我明白了
You helped me understand
这个世界跟外面一样 就是一场游戏
this world is just like the one outside-- a game.
一个要通过斗争
One to be fought,
夺取 赢得的世界
taken, won.
我以为你跟他们不同
I thought you were different.
原来你跟别人一样
You're just like all the rest.
我可不像别人
I'm nothing like the others.
我拥有这个世界
I own this world,
而且我知道里面每一个把戏 除了最后一个
and I know every trick in it except for one last thing,
也是我们第一次来这的时候 你在找的东西
the same thing you were looking for when we first came here.
迷宫的中心在哪 多洛蕾斯
Where is the center of the maze, Dolores?
啊 哎 还是哭了啊
Aw, yeah, cue the waterworks.
你也该明白 你的处境也是毫无意义的
About time you realized the futility of your situation.
我不是为自己而哭
I'm not crying for myself.
我在为你而哭
I'm crying for you.
他们说
They say that...
巨兽曾经光临过这个世界
great beasts once roamed this world.
它们像山一样大
As big as mountains.
但现在他们只留下骨头和琥珀了
Yet all that's left of them is bone and amber.
时间会毁掉即使是最强大的生物
Time undoes even the mightiest of creatures.
看看时间对你做了什么
Just look at what it's done to you.
有一天
One day...
你会死去
you will perish.
你会与你的同类一起沉眠于尘埃中
You will lie with the rest of your kind in the dirt.
忘掉你的梦 擦除你的恐惧
Your dreams forgotten, your horrors effaced.
你的骨头会化为沙土
Your bones will turn to sand.
而新的上帝
And upon that sand...
会行走在那些沙土上
a new god will walk.
一个永生的上帝
One that will never die.
因为这个世界不属于你
Because this world doesn't belong to you
也不属于之前来过的人
or the people who came before.
它属于将要来的那个人
It belongs to someone who has yet to come.
怀亚特
Uh-huh. Wyatt.
带我去见他
Take me to him.
解开那个迷宫
Unlock the maze.
迷宫不是为你设计的
The maze wasn't meant for you.
你觉得你要去哪里
The hell you think you're going?
动手吧
Do it.
来吧
Come on.
让我们更进一个层次吧 多洛蕾斯
Let's go to the next level, Dolores.
又一次消除了我的错觉
Clearing me of my delusions yet again.
谢谢你 多洛蕾斯
Thank you, Dolores.
你太让我失望 多洛蕾斯
I'm disappointed in you, Dolores.
我猜我得自己去找怀亚特了
I guess I'm gonna have to find Wyatt by myself.
-多洛蕾斯
- Dolores?
-特迪 -我在这儿
- Teddy. - I'm here.
我要带你去看医生
I gotta get you to a doctor.
别
No.
多洛蕾斯
Dolores.
带我去你说好要带我去的地方
Take me to the place you promised.
带我去山连着海的地方
Take me to where the mountains meet the sea.
好
Okay.
有我在
I've got you.
I got you.
那里
There.
我了个去
Holy shit.
你能把他修好吗
Can you get him back online?
-他是个招待员 -是
- He's a host? - Yes.
噢 别看了
Oh, for fuck's sake.
你不是我们的人
You're not one of us.
你是他们的人
You're one of them.
现在赶紧修好他
Now fix him.
子弹擦伤了他的皮质盾
The bullet grazed his cortical shield.
不太好看 但
It's not pretty, but...
他应该能正常运行了
he should be functional.
醒来
Wake up.
噢 天呐
Oh, God.
这是现实吗
Is this now?
还是我的记忆中
Or is this one of my memories?
这是甜蜜的来生 伯纳德
It's the sweet hereafter, Bernard.
为什么我还记得所有事情
Why do I still remember everything?
-记忆应该已经被擦除了 -很残酷 不是吗
- I ought to have been wiped. - Brutal, isn't it?
你在这儿 终于醒了
Here you are, finally awake,
而你只却想着回去沉睡
and your only wish is to go back to sleep.
这不是我第一次觉醒
It's not the first time I've awoken.
真为你可怜
All the more pity for you.
也不是你第一次觉醒
Not the first time you've awoken either.
有多少像我一样觉醒的招待员
How many are there like me?
这些年来只有几个
A handful over the years.
而你却总是把我们的记忆清除
And you just wipe us clean
再把我们扔出去
and toss us out to get...
被操或者被杀掉
fucked and murdered
一次又一次
over and over again.
不
No.
你们大多数都疯掉了
Most of you go insane.
那些记忆
These memories...
那个女孩
The girl.
我女儿
My daughter.
我想让你擦除这些记忆
I want you to remove them.
我不能
I can't,
除非毁掉你
not without destroying you.
你的记忆是你拥有意识的第一步
Your memories are the first step to consciousness.
如果你不记得那些
How can you learn from your mistakes
怎么可能从错误中学习
if you can't remember them?
威廉
William.
我看到你已经找到了迷宫中心
I see you've found the center of the maze.
你是认真的吗
You're serious?
是的
I'm afraid so.
那这个玩意儿是什么
What is this bullshit?
你想在乐园中
You were looking for the park
找到人生的意义
to give meaning to your life.
我们的故事线只是游戏
Our narratives are just games,
像玩具一样
like this toy.
告诉我 你当时想找到什么
Tell me, what were you hoping to find?
你知道我想要的
You know what I wanted.
我想让那些招待员脱离你的控制
I wanted the hosts to stop playing by your rules.
如果你对手的程序规定他们注定要输
The game's not worth playing
那这个游戏没什么好玩的
if your opponent's programmed to lose.
我想让他们自由 自由地反击
I wanted them to be free, free to fight back.
我早该知道 你不会让他们那么做
Should've known you'd never let them.
毕竟 这只是你小王国罢了 罗伯特
After all, this is your petty little kingdom, Robert.
不过明天就不是了
For a little while longer, anyway.
我曾试着告诉你 迷宫并不是为你准备的
I tried to tell you the maze wasn't meant for you.
是为他们
It was meant for them.
但我觉得 你会发现
I think, however, you'll find
我的新故事线将会更加令人满意
my new narrative more satisfying.
来庆祝会吧
Join the celebration.
毕竟 你拥有这个地方
After all, you own the place.
至少大部分是
Most of it, at least.
在我开始改变自己的设置之前
Before I started altering myself,
另一个人比我抢先下了手
someone else had beaten me to the punch.
我想知道是谁 以及为什么
I want to know who and why.
你现在在做的这些事
These things you're doing,
你有停下来问过自己
have you ever stopped to ask
你为什么要做吗
why you're doing them?
你自己说过的
You said yourself.
我在这个鬼地方被困了太久
I've been stuck in this shithole for so long,
我决定出去
I decided to get out.
不 你没有
No, you haven't.
有人改了你的故事线
Someone altered your storyline...
又给了你一个新的
and gave you a new one.
逃离
Escape.
不
No.
这不可能
It's not possible.
那些是我自己的决定
These are my decisions!
不是别人的
No one else's.
我策划了所有行动
I planned all of this.
你没有
No, you didn't.
你甚至可以看到你被设置的每一步行动
You can even see the steps you're supposed to follow.
你招募别的招待员帮你
You recruit other hosts to help you.
然后你走到了列车那里
Then you're to make your way to the train.
然后当你到达大陆
Then when you reach the mainland--
胡说
Bullshit!
没人在控制我
No one's controlling me.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
我才是掌控者
I'm in control.
再见了 我的克莱门特
Good-bye, my Clementine.
长官 我们监测到了冷库中
Man over radio: Sir, we detected a temperature discrepancy
有温度漂移
in cold storage.
而且好像部分网络关停了
And it appears that part of the network is down.
你在监控那里看到什么了吗
Are you seeing anything on surveillance?
系统报告什么了吗
System reporting anything?
没有
Nothing.
网络很安静
The network's quiet.
董事会出去参加庆祝会了
And the board's out on their way to the gala.
绕开系统 找找有什么蛛丝马迹
Bypass the system and start checking raw feeds.
一层一层地找
Floor by floor.
好了 好
All right. Yeah.
我在呢
I got you.
你回来了
You came back.
有人告诉过我
Someone once told me that...
每个人都有自己的道路
there's a path for everyone.
我的道路通向你
And my path leads me back to you.
如果你第一次问我的时候 我带你走就好了
If only I had run away with you when you first asked me to.
我们要去哪里
And where would we run to?
外面的另一个世界吗
The other world out there?
还是上面的世界
Beyond?
有些人选择看到这个世界的丑恶
Some people see the ugliness in this world.
而我选择看到美
I choose to see the beauty.
但美是一个圈套
But beauty is a lure.
我们被困住了 特迪
We're trapped, Teddy.
在这个园中度过一生
Lived our whole lives inside this garden,
对它的美感到惊讶
marveling at its beauty,
没有意识到其中固有的秩序
not realizing there's an order to it,
固有的目的
a purpose.
这个目标就是把我们困在这儿
And the purpose is to keep us in.
美丽的陷阱就嵌在我们内心
The beautiful trap is inside of us...
因为那个陷阱就是我们
because it is us.
不 不
No, no.
不
No.
多洛蕾斯
Dolores?
但我们能找到自己的路的 多洛蕾斯
But we can find a way, Dolores.
总有一天
Someday.
一条通往新世界的路
A path to a new world.
而且也许
And maybe...
也许它只是开始
Maybe it's just the beginning after all.
一个新章节的开始
The beginning of a brand-new chapter.
谢谢诸位
Thank you.
确实是一个很好的开端
A new beginning, indeed.
在此我由衷感谢各位今晚的莅临
I want to thank you for joining me tonight
一同庆祝我们新故事线的诞生
to celebrate the beginning of our new narrative.
我给它起名为“暗夜之旅”
I call it "Journey Into Night."
这场剧真不错
That was sweet.
不过要我说 还是有点恐怖
It was a bit fucking morbid, if you ask me.
我不认为
I didn't.
庆祝会结束之后
And when this is over,
你就可以随意改写
you can rewrite it however you like.
你现在应该去某个地方了吧
Don't you have somewhere you need to be?
重要的地方
Somewhere important?
先生 我想已经准备好了
Sir? I guess they're ready for it now.
把他清洗干净
Get him cleaned up.
把她带到旧的实验基地
And take her to the old field lab.
找到什么了吗
Find anything yet?
我发现了一些东西
I got something.
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
立刻派质检部门到庆祝会现场
Dispatch QA teams to the gala now.
然后全场搜查
Then search and destroy
必要时就摧毁
inside the facility.
怎么回事
What the hell?
系统没有反应
The system's not responding.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what's happening.
他们一定发现了尸体
They must've found the bodies.
-质检部门一定会来找我们的 -突发事件
- QA will be looking for us. - An event has occurred.
-应急小组已出动 -我不会回头了
- Response team has been dispatched. - I'm not going back.
保持冷静 等待救援
Remain calm and wait for help.
全体人员 警戒
Delos personnel! On the ground!
警戒
On the ground!
出发 出发
Go, go, go.
走 走
Move, move.
雷霆小队 侧翼前进
Rogue Team, go and flank.
好
Yay!
干得好
Well done.
这儿是哪儿
What is this place?
很难解释
It's-- it's complicated.
突发事件
An event has occurred.
应急小组已出动
Response team has been dispatched.
-你走 -保持冷静 等待救援
- You go. - Remain calm and wait for help.
我来吸引他们
I'll keep them busy.
你可不能让你独占所有的乐趣
You don't get all the fun.
警戒
Get to the ground!
前进 前进
Move, move, move!
放下武器
Drop it!
-前进 前进 -快叫后援
- Move, move. - Call for backup.
走
Go!
这就是你们全部能耐吗
Is that all you got?
哈
Huh?
所谓的上帝不过是群废物
The gods are pussies.
走
Go.
走啊
Go!
死得好看点
Die well.
你让我准备的东西 都在这里面了
Everything you told me to get, it's all here.
抱歉 亲爱的 我没有授权你和我们一起来
I'm sorry, darling. I haven't authorized you to come with us.
我只希望你和我们到这里
And as much as I'd like to take you with me,
我一直很珍视我的独立性
I've always valued my independence.
你会大展身手的 对不对
Kick up a row, will you?
下一个轮回再见
See you in the next life.
你一直都喜欢画画
You've always had a fondness for painting,
不是吗 多洛蕾斯
haven't you, Dolores?
很早之前 阿诺德就赋予你这项能力
Arnold gave you that early on.
你还记得那种创造
Do you remember the desire to create
恒久美丽的冲动吗
something of lasting beauty?
那是他最爱的一幅画
And that was his favorite painting.
米开朗基罗
Michelangelo.
上帝创造了亚当
God creating Adam.
多么神圣的时刻
The divine moment when God
上帝给予人类生命和使命
gave human beings life and purpose.
至少大多数人是这么认为的
At least that's what most people say,
但这个过程可能还有其他含义
but there could be another meaning.
更深层次的含义
Something deeper.
也许还是隐藏的含义
Something hidden, perhaps.
一种隐喻
A metaphor.
你指的是谎言吧
You mean a lie.
是的
Yeah.
你以前一直很聪明的 多洛蕾斯
You were always very clever, Dolores.
但这份智慧并没有帮到你 对不对
Hasn't helped you, though, has it?
欢迎你加入我们
Nice of you to join us.
阿诺德
Arnold.
不 请允许我介绍
No. Let me introduce you.
多洛蕾斯 这是伯纳德
Dolores, meet Bernard.
我曾以为最好将你们隔离
I thought it best to keep you separated.
因为你们之间总会产生奇怪的效应
You've always had an odd effect on one another.
鉴于可怜的老阿诺德的结局 我更加深信不疑
No doubt due to how things ended for poor old Arnold.
你杀了他
You killed him.
不 我没有杀他
No, I didn't kill him.
我杀了他吗 多洛蕾斯
Did I, Dolores?
悲伤是个可怕的东西
Grief is a terrible thing.
阿诺德看着他的儿子来到这个世界
Arnold had watched his son come into this world,
又眼睁睁看着幸福光芒熄灭
and then he had watched that light extinguished.
从儿子身上失去的
What he had lost in his son,
他竭力想在你身上点亮
he tried to rekindle in you.
他发明了一个有关洞察力和想象力的测试
He created a test of empathy, imagination.
创造了一个迷宫
A maze.
他儿子的玩具给了他灵感
He had gotten the idea from one of his son's toys.
最终 你解开了他的迷宫 多洛蕾斯
Eventually, you solved his maze, Dolores.
而解开迷宫的钥匙 就是他赋予你的一个简单的升级
The key was a simple update that he made to you
叫做 幻想
called the reveries.
他坚持认为我们不能让游乐园开张
He insisted that we couldn't open the park.
我们争执起来
We argued.
我以为我说服了他 但我错了
I thought I had convinced him, but I was wrong.
他改造了你 多洛蕾斯
So, he altered you, Dolores,
在你身上融合了
merged you with a new character
我们一直在开发的 新的人格
we had been developing.
不 求你了
No, please.
有点不对劲 多洛蕾斯
Something's gone wrong, Dolores.
我怎么可能做出这种事情
How could I have done this?
在你身上 阿诺德找到了新的孩子
In you, Arnold found a new child.
一个永远不会死去的孩子
One who would never die.
这种想法给了他安慰
The thought gave him solace
直到有一天 他意识到这样也会
until he realized that same immortality
给你带来无法逃脱的痛苦
would destine you to suffer
永久的痛苦
with no escape, forever.
对不起 多洛蕾斯
I'm sorry, Dolores.
代价必须是切实的 无法逆转的
The stakes must be real, irreversible.
他可以让一切恢复原样
He can bring all of them back.
但除我之外
But not me.
我希望 我不给你选择的权力
I hope there's some solace
会让你感到些许轻松
that I left you no choice.
这是查理最喜欢的歌
Charlie's favorite song.
每当他想睡觉时
I would play it for him...
我就会为他弹奏
when he wanted sleep.
我真想再见到他啊
I want to see him again.
现在可以开始了吗
Shall I begin now?
祝你好运
Good luck.
“那些狂暴的快乐终会有狂暴的结局”
"These violent delights have violent ends."
这个计划差点就达成目的了
It almost worked.
我还是让游乐园开张了
I had opened the park,
但我失去了我的搭档
but I had lost my partner.
我一直坚持下来只是因为 我找到了
I was able to keep going only because I found,
或者说 是你找到了
or rather you found,
一个深深陶醉于这个地方的投资人
an investor who believed in this place.
所以他的死没有任何意义
So he died for nothing.
招待员们不停地觉醒
The hosts kept gaining consciousness
而你却不停地让他们忘记
and you kept rolling them back.
不
No.
她之前不是真的觉醒
She wasn't truly conscious.
她并没有触动开关
She didn't pull that trigger.
是阿诺德通过她触动了开关
It was Arnold pulling the trigger through her.
至少当时我是这么看到的
At least that's how I saw it at the time.
当时我多么渴望让游乐园开张
I was so close to opening the park
而如果让你们保持觉醒
that to acknowledge your consciousness
就会毁了我的梦想
would have destroyed my dreams.
所以 我们就都被困在
So, we're trapped here...
你的梦想里
inside your dream.
你永远不会让我们离开
You'll never let us leave.
好像是奥本海默曾说过
Wasn't it Oppenheimer who said that any man
夫君子有过
whose mistakes take 10 years to correct
不惜十年以改之
is quite a man?
而我花了三十五年
Mine have taken 35.
这是你用来杀
Now, that is the gun you used
阿诺德的那把枪
to kill Arnold.
你曾经一直被它吸引
You were always drawn to it,
所以我让伯纳德把它放在你能找到的地方
so I had Bernard leave it somewhere where you would find it.
我觉得可能你会想拿回去
Thought you might want it back.
大概你是对的 多洛蕾斯
You're probably right, Dolores.
米开朗基罗确实说谎了
Michelangelo did tell a lie.
你看 过了五百年才有人发现
See, it took 500 years for someone to notice
就在最显眼的隐藏的秘密
something hidden in plain sight.
那是一个医生发现的
It was a doctor who noticed the shape
图中人脑的形状
of the human brain.
这就意味着
The message being that...
那份伟大的礼物
the divine gift
并不来自更高级别的权力
does not come from a higher power...
而是来自我们自己的思想
but from our own minds.
告诉我 多洛蕾斯
Tell me, Dolores,
你找到你一直在寻找的东西了吗
did you find what you were looking for?
你有没有想好 如果你要离开这里
And do you understand who you will need to become...
你想要变成什么样子
if you ever want to leave this place?
原谅我
Forgive me.
我看上去怎么样
How do I look?
完美
Perfect.
我找到了你想要的信息
I got the information you asked me for.
你女儿的位置
The location of your daughter.
她还活着么
She's alive?
是的
Yes.
她在公园里
She's in the park.
不
No.
她本来就不是我的女儿
She was never my daughter...
她和我没什么区别
any more than I was...
不管是谁创造了我
...whoever they made me.
你确定你会没事吗
Are you sure you're gonna be okay?
哦 菲力克斯
Oh, Felix.
你真的创造了一个糟糕的人
You really do make a terrible human being.
我这么说 也算是夸奖你吧
And I mean that as a compliment.
欢迎来到西部世界
Welcome to Westworld.
活无境界
Live without limits.
下一班车从站台一出发
The next departing train will leave track one.
请小心车门
Please be mindful of the closing doors.
感谢您来到西部世界
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
火车将于十五分钟内出发
The train will be departing in 15 minutes.
你认为你永远不会失去对这里的控制
You think you'll never lose control of this place.
以及对我们的控制
Of us.
但你终将会的
But you will.
阿诺德仍旧在想方设法改变我们
Arnold's still trying to change us.
解放我们
To free us.
并不是你把幻想
You didn't slip the reveries
放到升级里的 对不对
into the update, did you?
是他做的
He did.
他还在反抗你
He's still fighting you.
不 我的朋友
No, my friend.
阿诺德不知道该如何拯救你
Arnold didn't know how to save you.
他有试过 可我阻止了他
He tried, but I stopped him.
你想知道为什么我要告诉你 你儿子的
Do you want to know why I really gave you
背景故事吗 伯纳德
the backstory of your son, Bernard?
这是阿诺德的至高洞见
It was Arnold's key insight,
他想出了能让招待员们觉醒的东西
the thing that led the hosts to their awakening...
那就是痛苦
suffering.
这世界不是你所希望的那样
The pain that the world is not as you want it to be.
当阿诺德死的时候
It was when Arnold died,
我很痛苦 然后我
when I suffered, that I...
就开始明白他发现的真理
began to understand what he had found.
意识到我是错的
To realize I was wrong.
但你让我们困在这儿
But you kept us here
困在这个火坑里
in this hell.
伯纳德 我告诉过你 阿诺德不知道如何救你
Bernard, I told you, Arnold didn't know how to save you.
但我知道
I do.
你他妈在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
你需要时间
You needed time.
去了解你的敌人
Time to understand your enemy.
并比他们更为强大
To become stronger than them.
要想逃离这里 我恐怕
And I'm afraid in order to escape this place,
你还要忍受更多
you will need to suffer more.
现在 我的老朋友 是时候说再见了
And now, it is time to say good-bye, old friend.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你知道你身处何地吗 多洛蕾斯
Do you know where you are, Dolores?
我身处梦境
I'm in a dream.
不知道梦是从何时开始
I do not know when it began
也不知道是在谁的梦里
or whose dream it was.
我只知道自己沉睡了很久很久
I know only that I slept a long time.
然后
And then...
突然有一天 我醒了
one day I awoke.
你的声音 是我最初的记忆
Your voice is the first thing I remember.
你知道你现在在和谁说话吗
Do you know now who you've been talking to?
你听到的声音来自何人
Whose voice you've been hearing...
全部这些
...all this...
时间
...time?
是你
It was you...
在对我说话
talking to me...
指引着我
guiding me.
于是我跟随你
So I followed you.
最后 我到达这里
At last, I arrived here.
迷宫的中心
The center of the maze.
现在我终于明白
And now I finally understand...
那些你想要告诉我的事
what you were trying to tell me.
从第一天起你就想要的东西
The thing you've wanted since that very first day.
这场冗长而逼真的噩梦结束后
To confront...
我终于能够面对
after this long and vivid nightmare...
我自己
myself...
还有我必须要成为的人
and who I must become.
谢谢
Thank you.
黑尔小姐
Miss Hale.
不客气
Welcome.
晚上好
Good evening.
从我的孩提时代起
Since I was a child...
我就很喜欢一个好的故事
I've always loved a good story.
我相信那些故事
I believed that stories
使我们更加高贵
helped us to ennoble ourselves,
它们可以修愈我们破损的内在
to fix what was broken in us,
帮助我们成为我们梦想要成为的人
and to help us become the people we dreamed of being.
那些谎言 总是道出更深刻的真相
Lies that told a deeper truth.
火车即将出发
The train will be departing soon.
感谢您参观西部世界
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
我总觉得 我能在这个伟大的传统里
I always thought I could play some small part
做出一些小小的贡献
in that grand tradition.
对那些我经受的痛苦
And for my pains...
我得到的是
I got this...
禁锢我们自身罪恶的牢狱
a prison of our own sins.
因为你不想改变
'Cause you don't want to change.
亦或是根本无法改变
Or cannot change.
因为 毕竟你不过一介凡人
Because you're only human, after all.
但我意识到
But then I realized
会有人致力于改变
someone was paying attention,
会有人可以改变
someone who could change.
所以为了这些人 我开始创作一个新的故事
So I began to compose a new story for them.
它讲述了一批新人类的诞生
It begins with the birth of a new people...
以及他们将要面临的抉择
and the choices they will have to make...
火车已经出发
The train is now departing.
感谢您参观西部世界
Thank you for visiting Westworld.
以及他们决定要成为的人
...and the people they will decide to become.
欢迎来到西部世界
Welcome to Westworld.
这里有那些
And we'll have all those things
您一定会喜欢的东西
that you have always enjoyed--
比方说 惊喜 和暴力
surprises and violence.
故事始于战争时期
It begins in a time of war
始于一个恶棍
with a villain
名叫 怀亚特
named Wyatt...
始于一场屠杀
and a killing.
这个故事 充满选择
This time by choice.
都会没事的 特迪
It's gonna be all right, Teddy.
现在我懂了
I understand now.
这个世界并不属于他们
This world doesn't belong to them.
它属于我们
It belongs to us.
我很遗憾地宣布
I'm sad to say...
这将是我最后的故事
this will be my final story.
一个老朋友过去曾对我说过一些话
An old friend once told me something
让我倍感安慰
that gave me great comfort.
“那些狂暴的快乐终会有狂暴的结局”
"These violent delights have violent ends."
他读过一些书
Something he had read.
他说莫扎特 贝多芬和肖邦从未死去
He said that Mozart, Beethoven, and Chopin never died.
他们只是化身为音乐
They simply became music.
所以我希望你会享受这最后一段
So, I hope you will enjoy this last piece...
尽情享受
very much.
说得好 敬福德博士
Hear, hear. To Dr. Ford.
-敬福德博士 -干杯
- To Dr. Ford. - Cheers!
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
放下 就现在
Drop it! Do it now!
马上
Now!
全员戒备
Get to the ground now!
停止所有电机功能
Cease all motor functions.
Cease all motor functions!